Finding Aid for William D. Ford Papers 1955-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William D. Ford papers 1955-1995 1965-1995
Ford, William D. (William David), 1927-
9552 Aa 2
Democratic Congressman from Michigan's 15th District, 1964-1994, member of the Labor and Education Committee his entire career - becoming chairman in 1991, also chairman of Post Office and Civil Service Committee; papers include subject files, legislative and committee files, campaign material, photographs and videotapes.
152 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by William D. Ford (donor 8315 ) in January 1995.
The collection is open for research.
William D. Ford represented Michigan's Fifteenth Congressional District for thirty years, from 1964 to 1994. A Democrat, Ford was elected in the largely blue-collar district at the beginning of Lyndon Johnson's Great Society, and this determined the course of his congressional career. A strong proponent of government sponsored social programs and the labor movement, Ford has been described as "a crusty old pol, blunt, aggressive and partisan" [Duncan, p.762].
Ford was born August 6, 1927 in Detroit; his parents were autoworkers who had immigrated from Scotland. His working-class background and Depression era upbringing helped form his political views, and also proved to be a political asset in the Fifteenth District. Ford served in the Navy from 1944 to 1946, and the GI Bill enabled him to attend Nebraska State Teachers College (1946), Wayne State University (1947-1948), and the University of Denver, from which he received a Bachelor of Science degree in 1949, and a Juris Doctor degree in 1951.
Ford held political positions at the local level in Wayne County before being elected to the Michigan State Senate in 1962. When the Fifteenth District was created in 1964, he had the support of state Democratic leaders to take the seat and was elected with minimal opposition. Ford was never seriously challenged for the seat, consistently winning elections by at least 60% of the vote.
The relative ease with which Ford held his seat in Congress allowed him to concentrate his energies in Washington. He sat on the Education and Labor Committee for his entire congressional career, and became its chairman in 1991. The committee brought together Ford's two main interests, and he concentrated on building a reputation for handling education and labor legislation. He is perhaps best known for his work on college aid programs which targeted middle class voters, and he was also a proponent of vocational education. On labor issues, Ford worked for 14 years to pass a plant-closure notification bill, which became law in 1987 after intense negotiation and compromise by Ford.
Ford also served as chairman of the Post Office and Civil Service Committee, and regularly voted in favor of pay increases for federal employees and legislators; the relative security of his seat made the latter politically feasible. However, political pragmatism was a hallmark of Ford's career, and his legislative decisions were usually made with his constituents' reactions in mind. This was particularly true of his response to controversial issues such as court-enforced busing of schoolchildren, which he voted against, and economic protection of U.S. industry, which he strongly favored
Ford's congressional career reflects widespread changes in American political life. Fundraising at the start of his career tended to involve local events and traditional letter campaigns; by the 1980s, Ford depended heavily on financial support from Political Action Committees, and his fundraisers took place in Washington and New York City, as well as the Detroit area. He was also forced to deal with changes in his constituents' political views, as Fifteenth District voters became in many respects prototypical "Reagan Democrats" in the early 1980s. An extreme manifestation of many voters' shift away from Great Society liberalism was the candidacy of Gerald Carlson, a self-described "white rights" advocate who gathered nearly 40% of the vote against Ford in 1984.
In 1994, Ford chose not to run for office again, and retired from Congress to work for a Washington law firm.
Sources Consulted:
DeSimone, Bonnie. "The Quiet Ford", Ann Arbor News, July 1, 1985.
Duncan, Phil, ed. Congressional Quarterly's Politics in America, 1992. Washington, 1992, pp. 762-765.
Zuckman, Jill. "Will Clinton Restore Good Will to Education and Labor?", Congressional Quarterly Weekly Report, v.50, no.46, pp. 3671-3675.
The William D. Ford papers are organized into seven series Some series are further divided into chronological subseries.
Subject Files
1965-1969 [boxes 1-4]
1969-1971 [boxes 5-9]
1971-1974 [boxes 10-15]
1974-1976 [boxes 16-21]
1976-1979 [boxes 22-27]
1980 [boxes 150-151]
1980-1981 [boxes 27-30]
1982-1984 [boxes 31-37]
1984-1986 [boxes 38-43]
1986-1988 [boxes 43-48]
1988-1990 [boxes 49-53]
1990-1992 [boxes 54-61]
1992-1993 [boxes 62-67]
1993-1994 [boxes 67-73]
1994-1995 [boxes 73-76]
Busing Correspondence [boxes 77-78]
Legislative Files
1965-1967 [boxes 79-81]
1967-1969 [boxes 82-84]
1970-1971 [boxes 85-87]
1971-1972 [box 151]
1973-1974 [boxes 88-89 and boxes 151-152]
1975-1980 [boxes 90-94]
Committee Files
Education and Labor Committee
Topical Files, 1969-1994 [boxes 95-101]
Floor Statements and Extensions of Remarks, 1990-1994 [box 101]
Memos from Committee Staff, 1994 [box 101]
Michigan Material, 1990-1994 [box 102]
Speeches, 1990-1994 [box 103]
Testimony, 1990-1994 [box 103]
Topical Briefing Notes and Correspondence, 1990-1994 [box 103]
Mass Mailings, 1991-1994 [boxes 103-109]
Subcommittees
Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Educational Subcommittee, 1991-1994 [boxes 109-116]
Post-Secondary Education Subcommittee, 1977-1994 [boxes 116-120]
Post Office and Civil Service Committee [POCS], 1975-1983 [boxes 120-121]
Staff Files: Ross Eisenbrey, 1979-1988 [boxes 121-125]
Campaign Material
1962-1990 [boxes 126-132]
Gerald Carlson Information Files (including audiotapes of Carlson), 1980-1986 [box 132]
Public Relations
Michigan State Senate Activities, 1960-1965 [box 133]
Speeches, 1965-1991 [boxes 133-136]
Press Releases, 1964-1981 [box 136]
Press Logs, 1989-1993 [box 137]
Congressional Record Inserts and Bills Introduced, 1967-1976 [boxes 137-139]
Daily Schedules, 1968-1969 and 1982-1991 [box 140]
District Office Reports, 1965-1971 [box 140]
Biographies, Newsclippings and Publicity, 1964-1992 [box 140]
VIP Scrapbooks, 1968-1983 [boxes 141-142]
Visual Material
Photographs, 1955-1994 [boxes 143-144]
Videotapes, 1987-1994 [boxes 145-149]
The William D. Ford papers are divided into seven series: Subject Files, Legislative Files, Committee Files, Campaign Material, Public Relations, Photographs, and Audiovisual Material. The collection is primarily an office file which documents Ford's activities as a local representative, federal legislator and politician. Constituents' opinions and concerns are represented as well, particularly in the correspondence and questionnaire response files.
Subjects:
Ford, William D. (William David), 1927-; Abortion--Law and legislation--United States.; Busing for school integration--United States.; Civil service--Law and legislation--United States.; Educational law and legislation--United States.; Elections--Michigan--1964.; Elections--Michigan--1966.; Elections--Michigan--1968.; Elections--Michigan--1970.; Elections--Michigan--1972.; Elections--Michigan--1974.; Elections--Michigan--1976.; Elections--Michigan--1978.; Elections--Michigan--1980.; Elections--Michigan--1982.; Elections--Michigan--1984.; Elections--Michigan--1986.; Elections--Michigan--1988.; Elections--Michigan--1990.; Labor laws and legislation--United States.; Legislators--United States.; Postal service--Law and legislation--United States.; Postsecondary education--United States.; United States. Congress. House.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Education and Labor.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; United States--Politics and government--1974-1977.; United States--Politics and government--1977-1981.; United States--Politics and government--1981-1989.; United States--Politics and government--1989-1993.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Draft resisters--United States.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Protest movements.; Watergate affair, 1972-1974.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Ford, William D. (William David), 1927-; Legislative bodies.; Legislators--United States.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.; Picnics.; Political elections.; Political parades and rallies.; Politics and government.; Presidents and the Congress.; United States. Congress. House.; Agnew, Spiro T., 1918-1996.; Albert, Carl Bert, 1908-2000; Begin, Menachem, 1913-1992; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Chavez, Cesar, 1927-1993; Clinton, Bill, 1946-; Clinton, Hillary Rodham.; Conyers, John, 1929-; Dingell, John D.; Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1926-; Dukakis, Michael S. (Michael Stanley), 1933-; Ferency, Zolton A., 1922-1993; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Harkin, Tom.; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Jackson, Henry M. (Henry Martin), 1912-1983.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; McCormack, John W., 1891-1980.; Mondale, Walter F., 1928-; O'Neill, Tip.; Rabin, Yitzhak, 1922-1995; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970.; Richards, Ann, 1933-2006; Riegle, Donald W., 1938-; Rusk, Dean, 1909-1994; Shriver, Sargent, 1915-2011; Swainson, John B. (John Burley), 1925-1994.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Young, Coleman A.
Genre/Form:
Videotapes.; Photographs.
- Subject Files 1965-1995, 79 linear feet
  Subject Files (79 linear feet; 1965-1995) include correspondence, memoranda, questionnaires and background material. The files are arranged chronologically by year, and then alphabetically by topic within each year. The original office filing systems have been maintained; files dating from 1965 to 1979 are listed by slightly idiosyncratic folder headings, while files dating from 1980 to 1995 are arranged using standardized subject headings, followed by more detailed subheadings. The subheadings are not used on this boxlist so that, for example, a folder listed as "Migrant Workers" in the first section of the subject files would be found under the "Labor" section of the post-1980 files.
  Most of the constituent correspondence is arranged by topic, and major controversies of the time are well represented, including the Vietnam War, amnesty for draft dodgers, Watergate, economic issues and abortion. Examples of postcard campaigns and form letters have been kept, but the bulk of this type of correspondence was discarded.
  Constituent correspondence regarding court enforced integration of public schools is listed as "Busing" in the chronological Subject Files from the early 1970s. However, the sheer volume of busing correspondence compelled Ford's staff to maintain separate "Busing" files as well, and these letters are stored out of chronological order in boxes 77 and 78. These files document what was perhaps the most vehemently debated issue in the Fifteenth District during Ford's tenure in congress.
  - 1965-1966
    - Abortion (Box 1)
    - Academies (Box 1)
    - Ad Hoc Subcommittee on the War on Poverty (Box 1)
    - Adult Basic Education (Box 1)
    - AFL-CIO (Box 1)
    - Agency for International Development (Box 1)
    - Agriculture (Box 1)
    - Aid to Dependent Children (Box 1)
    - Aid to Education, State (Box 1)
    - Air Force (Box 1)
    - American Civil Liberties Union [ACLU] (Box 1)
    - American Friends Service Committee (Box 1)
    - American Indians (Box 1)
    - American Legion (Box 1)
    - Americans for Democratic Action [ADA] (Box 1)
    - Architect of the Capitol (Box 1)
    - Arlington Cemetery Burial (Box 1)
    - Armed Forces (Box 1)
    - Army, Department of (Box 1)
    - Auto Insurance (Box 1)
    - Auto Safety (Box 1)
    - Birds (Box 1)
    - Busing (Box 1)
    - Children (Box 1)
    - Civil Rights (Box 1)
    - Civil Service (Box 1)
    - Communism (Box 1)
    - Cranks (Box 1)
    - Customs (Federal Bureau) (Box 1)
    - Duties of a Congressman (Box 1)
    - Employment Assistance (Box 1)
    - Federal Housing Administration (Box 1)
    - Fluoridation (Box 1)
    - Foreign Policy (Box 1)
    - General Legislation (Box 1)
    - Great Society (Box 1)
    - Head Start (Box 1)
    - House Unamerican Activities Committee [HUAC] (Box 1)
    - Housing and Urban Development Act (Box 1)
    - Income Tax Sharing (Box 1)
    - Inflation (Box 1)
    - Local Income Tax (Box 1)
    - Medicare (Box 1)
    - Michigan, University of (Box 1)
    - Migrant Workers (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 1)
    - Newsletter comments (Box 1)
    - Obscenity (Box 1)
    - Primary and Secondary Education Act (Box 1)
    - Questionnaire replies (Box 1)
    - Selective service (Box 1)
    - Sumpter NAACP (Box 1)
    - Tax Cut and Reform (Box 1)
    - Tent City, Mississippi (Box 1)
    - Vietnam (Box 1)
    - Vocational Rehabilitation Center (Box 1)
    - Water Pollution (Box 1)
  - 1966-1967
    - Ann Arbor Democratic Party (Box 2)
    - Army (Box 2)
    - Auto Safety (Box 2)
    - Carmichael, Stokely (Box 2)
    - Davidson Brothers, Inc. (Box 2)
    - Detroit Metropolitan Airport (Box 2)
    - Detroit Poverty Hearings (Box 2)
    - Detroit Riots (Box 2)
    - Education Assistance (Box 2)
    - Elementary and Secondary Education Act (Box 2)
    - Federal Subsidy Programs (Box 2)
    - Ford Local 600 (Box 2)
    - Great Society Democratic Clun (Box 2)
    - Gun Legislation (Box 2)
    - Labor Day (Box 2)
    - Michigan Department of Education (Box 2)
    - Michigan Neighborhood Youth Corps (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - National Association of Letter Carriers (Box 2)
    - National Guard (Box 2)
    - National Historic Landmarks (Box 2)
    - National Rivers and Harbors Congress (Box 2)
    - National Star Route Carriers Association (Box 2)
    - National Teacher Corps (Box 2)
    - Near East (Box 2)
    - Ocean Foods Institute (Box 2)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity [OEO] (Box 2)
    - Patronage (Box 2)
    - Pornography (Box 2)
    - Questionnaires (Box 2)
    - Selective Service (Box 2)
    - Social Security (Box 2)
    - Teachers' Strikes (Box 2)
    - Teamsters (Box 2)
    - Unidentified Flying Objects (Box 2)
    - United Auto Workers (Box 2)
    - United Nations (Box 2)
    - Veterans Administration (Box 3)
    - Vietnam (Box 3)
    - War on Poverty (Box 3)
    - Water Resources (Box 3)
    - Wayne County Headstart Program (Box 3)
    - Wayne County Intermediate School District (Box 3)
    - Wayne County Office of Economic Opportunity [OEO] (Box 3)
    - "Why Vietnam?" (Box 3)
    - World War I Veterans (Box 3)
    - Wyandotte Chemicals (Box 3)
  - 1967-1968
    - 90th Congress-Opening and Organization (Box 3)
    - Crime (Box 3)
    - Democratic State Central Committee, Michigan (Box 3)
    - Democratic State Convention (Box 3)
    - Democratic National Convention (Box 3)
    - Detroit Board of Education (Box 3)
    - Detroit Newspaper Strike (Box 3)
    - Detroit River (Box 3)
    - Draft Eastern Michigan University (Box 3)
    - Federal Aviation administration (Box 3)
    - Federal Employee Pay Raise (Box 3)
    - Foreign Affairs (Box 3)
    - Gun Control (Box 3)
    - Hunger In America (Box 3)
    - Inflation (Box 3)
    - Manpower Programs (Box 3)
    - Medicare (Box 3)
    - Middle East (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 3)
    - Newsletter responses (Box 3)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity [OEO] (Box 3)
    - Political (Box 3)
    - Poor Peoples' March (Box 3)
    - Powell v. Gibbons (Box 3)
    - Pueblo Incident (Box 3)
    - Questionnaire responses (Box 4)
    - Riots-Detroit (Box 4)
    - Riots-General (Box 4)
    - School Prayer (Box 4)
    - Selective Service (Box 4)
    - Senior Citizens (Box 4)
    - Taylor Center High School (Box 4)
    - Teamsters (Box 4)
    - United Auto Workers (Box 4)
    - Urban Problems (Box 4)
    - VISTA (Box 4)
    - Wayne County Economic Opportunity Committee (Box 4)
    - Wayne County Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 4)
    - Veterans Administration (Box 4)
    - Vietnam (Box 4)
  - 1968-1969
    - Biafra (Box 4)
    - Crime (Box 4)
    - Gun Control (Box 4)
    - Indian Affairs (Box 4)
    - Lansing Political Clinic for Teachers (Box 4)
    - Michigan Conference of Concerned Democrats (Box 4)
    - Middle East Crises (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire replies (Box 4)
    - White House Conference on Children and Youth (Box 4)
  - 1969-1970
    - AFL-CIO (Box 5)
    - Air Traffic Controllers (Box 5)
    - Alcohol (Box 5)
    - Allen Park V.A. Hospital (Box 5)
    - American Security Council (Box 5)
    - Annual Income (Box 5)
    - Anti-ballistic Missiles (Box 5)
    - Anti-trust (Box 5)
    - Area Wages (Box 5)
    - "Birch Barks" (Box 5)
    - Census (Box 5)
    - Child Abuse (Box 5)
    - Congressional Box Scores (Box 5)
    - Conservation (Box 5)
    - Cranks (Box 5)
    - Crime (Box 5)
    - Defense Department (Box 5)
    - Democratic Party (Box 5)
    - Democratic Study Group (Box 5)
    - Detroit Metropolitan Airport (Box 5)
    - Detroit-Shooting (Box 5)
    - Discrimination (Box 5)
    - Dow Chemical Company (Box 5)
    - Draft (Box 5)
    - Drug Control (Box 5)
    - Education (Box 5)
    - Election (Box 6)
    - Environmental Quality (Box 6)
    - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 6)
    - Food and Drug Administration (Box 6)
    - Foreign Imports (Box 6)
    - Foreign Trade (Box 6)
    - Gasoline Prices (Box 6)
    - Grape Boycott (Box 6)
    - Great Lakes Task Force (Box 6)
    - Head Start (Box 6)
    - Health (Box 6)
    - Health Service for Detroit and Wayne County (Box 6)
    - Hijacking Airplanes (Box 6)
    - Homestead Tax Exemption (Box 6)
    - Housing and Urban Development Department [HUD] (Box 6)
    - Hunger (Box 6)
    - Indians (Box 6)
    - Inflation (Box 6)
    - Internal Revenue Service (Box 6)
    - Interior Department (Box 6)
    - Job Corps (Box 6)
    - Laos (Box 6)
    - Library of Congress (Box 6)
    - Marijuana (Box 6)
    - Medicaid (Box 6)
    - Melvindale High School Class Reunion (Box 6)
    - Michigan Consolidated Gas Company (Box 6)
    - Michigan Good Roads Federation (Box 6)
    - Michigan Highway Department (Box 6)
    - Michigan State Education and Welfare Proposals (Box 6)
    - Michigan State University (Box 6)
    - Michigan Vocational Education (Box 6)
    - Middle East (Box 6)
    - Migrant Farm Workers (Box 6)
    - Military (Box 6)
    - Milliken, Governor William (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 6)
    - Michigan-Ohio Regional Education Laboratory (Box 6)
    - Municipal Officials' Conference (Box 6)
    - National Defense Education Act [NDEA] Loan Forgiveness (Box 6)
    - National Federation of Independent Business (Box 6)
    - National Foundation for the Arts and Humanities (Box 6)
    - National Guard (Box 6)
    - National Priorities (Box 6)
    - Navy (Box 6)
    - Neighborhood Youth Corps (Box 6)
    - Newsletter Responses (Box 6)
    - Nixon Vetoes (Box 6)
    - Nurses (Box 6)
    - Nursing Homes (Box 6)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity [OEO] (Box 6)
    - Overpopulation (Box 6)
    - Parochial School Aid (Box 6)
    - Pay Television (Box 6)
    - Peoples' Community Hospital Authority (Box 6)
    - Personal (Box 6)
    - Pollution (Box 6)
    - Poor (Box 6)
    - Pornography (Box 6)
    - Post Office (Box 6)
    - Post Office, cont. (Box 7)
    - Postal Strike (Box 7)
    - Prayer (Box 7)
    - Presidential Libraries (Box 7)
    - Press Party (Box 7)
    - Prisoners of War (Box 7)
    - Property Taxes (Box 7)
    - Prospect Manufacturing and Engineering Company (Box 7)
    - Public Recreation Programs (Box 7)
    - Questionnaires (Box 7)
    - Race Relations (Box 7)
    - Radio Tapings (Box 7)
    - Railroad Employees (Box 7)
    - Ready-Address-to Congressmen Program (Jaycees) (Box 7)
    - Rhodesia (Box 7)
    - Robert Kennedy Memorial (Box 7)
    - Rouge River (Box 7)
    - Salary Increase for Members of Congress (Box 7)
    - School Busing (Box 7)
    - School Lunch (Detroit) (Box 7)
    - Senior Citizens (Box 7)
    - Seniority (Box 7)
    - Sex Education (Box 7)
    - Sleeping Bear Dunes (Box 7)
    - Small Business Administration (Box 7)
    - Social Security (Box 7)
    - Sole Surviving Sons (Box 7)
    - Space (Box 7)
    - Speech Materials (Box 7)
    - Steelworkers (Box 7)
    - Student Unrest (Box 7)
    - Subsidies (Box 7)
    - Supreme Court (Box 7)
    - Tax Reform (Box 7)
    - Teacher Corps, Urban (Box 7)
    - Times-Herald (Box 7)
    - UNICEF (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Flying Objects (Box 7)
    - United Federation of Postal Clerks (Box 7)
    - Urban Renewal (Box 7)
    - Veterans (Box 8)
    - Vietnam (Box 8)
    - Votes in Congress, Economy (Box 8)
    - Water Pollution (Box 8)
    - Wayne County Road Commissioners (Box 8)
    - Welfare (Box 8)
    - White Panthers (Box 8)
  - 1970-1971
    - Advertisements Placed (Box 8)
    - Advocates (Box 8)
    - AFL-CIO (Box 8)
    - Agriculture (Box 8)
    - Alcohol Abuse (Box 8)
    - American Federation of Government Employees (Box 8)
    - Animal Welfare (Box 8)
    - Army (Box 8)
    - CBS (Box 8)
    - Commerce, Department of (Box 8)
    - Committee Assignments (Box 8)
    - Congress (Box 8)
    - Congressional Record Inserts (Box 8)
    - Congressional Leadership for the Future (Sargent Shriver) (Box 8)
    - Democratic Party (Box 8)
    - Detroit (Box 8)
    - Detroit Metropolitan Airport (Box 8)
    - District Office Memos (Box 8)
    - Eastern Michigan University (Box 8)
    - Ecorse Creek (Box 8)
    - Education (Box 8)
    - Education and Labor Committee (Box 8)
    - Electoral Reform (Box 8)
    - Ethnic Groups (Box 8)
    - Farmers Union (Box 8)
    - Federal Communication Commission (Box 8)
    - Federal Trade Commission (Box 8)
    - Firefighters (Box 8)
    - General Motors Corporation (Box 8)
    - Immigration and Naturalization (Box 8)
    - Indians (Box 8)
    - Labor Department (Box 9)
    - Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam (Box 9)
    - Legal Aid (Box 9)
    - Libraries (Box 9)
    - Lockheed (Box 9)
    - Michigan Department of Natural Resources (Box 9)
    - National Federation of Independent Unions (Box 9)
    - Office Administration (Box 9)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 9)
    - Overseas Schools (Box 9)
    - Pentagon (Box 9)
    - Peoples Community Hospital Authority (PCHA) (Box 9)
    - Pollution (Box 9)
    - Pornography (Box 9)
    - Post Office (Box 9)
    - Questionnaires (Box 9)
    - Railroad Retirement (Box 9)
    - Railway Labor (Box 9)
    - Re-apportionment (Box 9)
    - School Lunch (Box 9)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission (Box 9)
    - State Legislatures (Box 9)
    - Taxation (Box 9)
    - Time Magazine (Box 9)
    - Trade Bill (Box 9)
    - Transportation (Box 9)
    - Tributes (Box 9)
    - UAW Retirees (Box 9)
    - United nations (Box 9)
    - Unesco (Box 9)
    - United Steel Workers (Box 9)
    - Urban Renewal (Box 9)
    - Veterans (Box 9)
    - Vietnam (Box 9)
    - VISTA (Box 9)
    - Voters (Box 9)
    - Wayne County Community College (Box 9)
    - Wayne County Program Development and Coordination (Box 9)
    - Wayne County Road Commission (Box 9)
    - Welfare (Box 9)
    - Willow Run Airport (Box 9)
  - 1971-1972
    - Abortion (Box 10)
    - American Medical Association (Box 10)
    - American Postal Workers Union (Box 10)
    - Amnesty (Box 10)
    - Association of Civilian Technicians (Box 10)
    - Atomic Energy Commission (Box 10)
    - Communities United for Action (Box 10)